Mark Ryan Guamos



ryan.guamos@gmail.com



+639178014376



linkedin.com/in/mark-ryan-guamos

Summary

A Senior Software Engineer with 10+ years of professional experience, specializing in fullstack development, Java, SQL, and Javascript. A proven track record of managing large scale software engineering projects to support cloud deployments and integrations.

Experience

Software Engineer

Amihan Solutions

Jul 2022 - Present (7 months)

- · Helped with fixing bugs and adding features.
- Participated in integrating with clients and third-party providers.
- Provided application support for multiple clients.
- · Utilized AWS cloud services

Software Engineer

Shang Software Solutions

Nov 2017 - Jun 2022 (4 years 8 months)

- Improved existing applications and fixed concurrency issues.
- Automated processes and regression tests using Selenium.
- · Developed monitoring tools.
- Utilized DevOps tools like CI/CD, Docker, and Kubernetes
- · Developed several microservices.
- Helped in migrating on-premise applications to Azure.

Software Engineer

Yondu, Inc.

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year 3 months)

- Helped with fixing bugs and SQL optimizations.
- · Mentored some developers on fullstack development.
- Participated in the revamping of a legacy application.

Software Engineer

iServe Customer Management Solutions Inc.

Dec 2014 - Jul 2016 (1 year 8 months)

- · Led a small team of developers.
- Developed a Case Management System for a gov't agency.

• Mentored some junior developers.

Java Developer

New World Solutions Ltd

Jan 2013 - Nov 2014 (1 year 11 months)

- Helped with fixing bugs and adding features.
- · Assisted with QA testing.

Java Developer

ODGS

Jan 2012 - Jan 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Helped with fixing bugs and provided application support.

Java Developer

AATi Technologies

Nov 2010 - Sep 2011 (11 months)

- Helped with small bug fixes while learning Java and several Java frameworks.
- Developed a small tool that parses handwritten values in a scanned form using OCR.

Education

International Electronics and Technical Institue

Bachelor's Degree, Information Technology 2006 - 2010

Skills

Java • Spring Framework • Spring Boot • Hibernate • JavaScript • SQL • React.js • Angular • Blockchain • web3.js